<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides by Gunther</title>
    <link>https://gunther.link/</link>
    <description>Guides by Gunther</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://gunther.link/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GrapheneOS: User Impressions</title>
      <link>https://gunther.link/posts/grapheneos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunther.link/posts/grapheneos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started focusing on moving toward more privacy-friendly software and services, I knew that at some point I would want to install a custom OS on my phone. I&amp;rsquo;ve always used Android as my mobile OS, and Android, being a Google product, is of course used to gather data on its users. While I was not as privacy-conscious when I bought my current phone a few years ago, by good fortune the model I purchased was a Google Pixel 3a, which is compatible with some top-tier custom OSes, including CalyxOS and GrapheneOS. The phone is getting somewhat old at this point (though it still runs pretty smoothly) and the Pixel 3a reaching end-of-life and no longer receiving software updates (including security updates) from Google was extra motivation for me to consider installing a custom OS. Even so, I was a bit nervous to install a new OS on the phone since doing so involves formatting the phone and entails a chance of bricking the device. I spent quite a while tinkering with various non-Google backup solutions for my phone so that I could import all my data to the formatted device without needing to rely on Google (&lt;a href=&#34;https://syncthing.net/&#34;&gt;Syncthing&lt;/a&gt; was very useful for this). After I felt comfortable with my backups, I finally made the plunge and installed GrapheneOS on my device. I thought my experiences could potentially be useful to others who are considering a custom mobile OS and decided to write a post about it. This will not be a full review of GrapheneOS, but merely my impressions installing and using the software. I will be writing about GrapheneOS from the perspective of a layman/user, as I&amp;rsquo;m not qualified to evaluate GrapheneOS from a technical standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;choosing-the-os&#34; &gt;Choosing the OS
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#choosing-the-os&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While there are quite a number of &amp;ldquo;deGoogled&amp;rdquo; and/or privacy-focused custom OSes that were available for my phone, the two that were most often recommended for Google Pixels were CalyxOS and GrapheneOS. Both are based on AOSP (Android Open-Source Project) and are focused on making Android a more privacy-friendly OS and limiting Google&amp;rsquo;s control over the data stored on and generated from the device. Both also preserve &lt;a href=&#34;https://source.android.com/docs/security/features/verifiedboot&#34;&gt;Android&amp;rsquo;s verified boot feature&lt;/a&gt;, a security feature which is often not preserved in custom OSes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was leaning more toward CalyxOS at first, the more I researched, the more I felt that GrapheneOS was the better option. While CalyxOS does preserve the security features of stock Android well (unlike other custom AOSP-based OSes which do not), GrapheneOS not only preserves the security features in stock Android, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://grapheneos.org/features#grapheneos&#34;&gt;improves on them in a variety of ways&lt;/a&gt;. Additonally, GrapheneOS has a better track record than CalyxOS of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacyguides.org/android/grapheneos-vs-calyxos/#update-frequency&#34;&gt;merging upstream updates on time&lt;/a&gt;, which is also important for device security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two factors that continued to pull me toward CalyxOS, however. The first was CalyxOS&amp;rsquo; support for MicroG, which mimics Google Play Services and allows many apps that rely on Google Play Services to run on the phone even without Google Play Services installed. While having a phone without Google Play Services installed on it at all sounds nice in theory, in practice many of the apps I need day-to-day require Google Play Services to function properly. However, somewhat recently GrapheneOS added support for sandboxed Google Play Services, which allows Google Play Services to be installed on the phone while limiting its permissions and general access as compared to Google Play Services on stock Android. MicroG and sandboxed Google Play Services are two different models of attempting to limit Google&amp;rsquo;s control over the device while preserving compatibility. MicroG is an open-source reimplementation of Google Play Services, which spoofs stock Google Play Services, requiring all the same elevated permissions that Google Play Services does and communicating with Google&amp;rsquo;s servers. Sandboxed Google Play Services on the other hand, uses the standard, proprietary Google Play Services software, but treats it as a user app and denies many of the elevated permissions that stock Google Play Services and MicroG both require in order to work. Both solutions still send some information to Google and provide imperfect compatibility with apps that require Google Play Services. Nevertheless, by all reports sandboxed Google Play Services provides at least as much compatibility as MicroG and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacyguides.org/android/grapheneos-vs-calyxos/#sandboxed-google-play-vs-privileged-microg&#34;&gt;seems to be a more secure implementation as well&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second factor that pulled me toward CalyxOS was the drama surrounding GrapheneOS and its founder and lead developer, Daniel Micay. GrapheneOS started its life as CopperheadOS, but after a feud between Micay and James Donaldson, Copperhead&amp;rsquo;s CEO, Micay left Copperhead and started GrapheneOS. Both Micay and Donaldson claim that they have the rights to the CopperheadOS source code and are &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CopperheadOS#License_change_and_departure_of_Daniel_Micay&#34;&gt;currently in a legal dispute over these rights&lt;/a&gt;. Given that Micay was clearly the technical brains behind CopperheadOS and the fact that &lt;a href=&#34;https://mamushi.io/2021/04/12/departing-from-copperhead/&#34;&gt;other of Donaldson&amp;rsquo;s former business associates aren&amp;rsquo;t very complimentary of him&lt;/a&gt;, this dispute alone is not very concerning. However, Micay, and by extension the GrapheneOS project and community, have gotten in feuds with a number of other privacy-focused and FOSS projects. The list includes but is not limited to: &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Dx7CZ-2Bajg&#34;&gt;Techlore&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DanielMicay/status/1512254304006119427&#34;&gt;CalyxOS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.f-droid.org/t/what-are-the-issues-fdroid-have-about-security/17520&#34;&gt;F-Droid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20210613225002/https://sethsimmons.me/posts/community-drama-and-mobile-os/&#34;&gt;Seth For Privacy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bromite/bromite/issues/2141&#34;&gt;Bromite&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, is it possible that all of these projects are in cahoots against Micay and GrapheneOS and have organized misinformation and harassment campaigns against the project as Micay claims? I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen any evidence of these campaigns myself, but sure, it&amp;rsquo;s possible. Is it also possible and perhaps more likely that Micay is simply a little paranoid, maybe because of his bad experiences at Copperhead? Absolutely. However, while Micay has been somewhat acrimonious toward many of these projects, he seems genuine in believing that these other projects are looking to damage GrapheneOS and his behavior toward them generally seems to be better characterized as unprofessional rather than abusive. While that is still unfortunate, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a good reason not to use and even support the GrapheneOS project, especially when many of the projects that GrapheneOS feuds with admit that GrapheneOS is an excellent OS and that Micay is a genius developer. It is still concerning that GrapheneOS has such poor relationships with other FOSS projects since the success and longevity of FOSS projects is often dependent on incorporating code from other projects. However, GrapehenOS has a whole team of talented developers and contributors, so perhaps they can continue making a successful product even without collaboration with other prominent FOSS projects. Ultimately, this drama, while somewhat concerning, did not seem like a good reason for me to choose an alternative custom OS over Graphene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34; &gt;Installation
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#installation&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I have never installed a custom OS on my phone before, I do have some experience installing custom firmware on video game consoles and by comparison, installing GrapheneOS is an absolute breeze. I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://grapheneos.org/install/web&#34;&gt;web installer&lt;/a&gt; for the installation process and doing so was very straightforward. Once you have your phone connected to your PC, the process is basically just pressing a few buttons while the web installer does all the hard work for you. I did run into problems when trying to use UnGoogled Chromium as the browser for the install, but the good folks the GrapheneOS Matrix room informed me that while vanilla Chromium is compatible with the web installer, UnGoogled Chromium is not. I ended up using Brave for the install, which worked very well and I didn&amp;rsquo;t hit any other snags in the installation process. Even if you have minimal technical expertise, using the web installer should be no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ux&#34; &gt;UX
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ux&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After installing GrapheneOS, the setup experience was very similar to stock Android with the obvious exception of not needing a Google account. By default the UI is very bare, but this is by design. The only apps that are installed by default include reskinned versions of some basic AOSP apps (Phone, Contacts, Messages, Settings, etc.), Vanadium (GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; hardened version of Chromium), and GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;app store&amp;rdquo;. I put &amp;ldquo;app store&amp;rdquo; in quotes since it is only used for GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; first-party apps, most of which are system apps which come preinstalled. The app store also includes sandboxed Google Play Services, though I will discuss that more in-depth in a bit. The general UI of the phone is basically identical to stock Android and should be familiar to anyone who is used to the stock version of the OS. After adding some apps and a custom background, my phone with GrapheneOS looks mostly indistinguishable from when it was running stock Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sandboxed-google-play-services&#34; &gt;Sandboxed Google Play Services
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#sandboxed-google-play-services&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I could get some apps running on GrapheneOS as-is, the vast majority of apps require Google Play Services to work properly. Installing sandboxed Google Play Services from Graphene&amp;rsquo;s app store is pretty simple and can be done in a few taps. While some basic Google Play Services functionality can work without being logged in to a Google account, most apps will need the full Google Play Services suite, which includes the Google Play Store and in order for the Play Store to function, you will need to log in to a Google account. You can of course make a &amp;ldquo;throwaway&amp;rdquo; account specifically for this purpose, though it would not surprise me if Google has ways of correlating accounts with each other, especially if you ever log in to your personal account on the same device. You can then use the Google Play Store to install apps, though you can of course also use F-Droid or Aurora Store. Once the full Google Play Services suite was installed and I was logged into my Google account, I was really impressed with the app compatibility. I did struggle a little bit with some apps at first, but after some experimenting and tweaking, I have yet to encounter a single app that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get working with sandboxed Google Play Services. This even includes some banking apps, which apparently don&amp;rsquo;t always work well with sandboxed Google Play Services. You can further limit Google Play Services by installing it only in a specific user profile or a work profile, though I am currently just using it on the main user profile for the sake of convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-features&#34; &gt;Security Features
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#security-features&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; security features are under the hood, but there are some that you will notice. First is the obvious lack of any proprietary Google apps on the phone by default, as I have already discussed. Second, is the expanded permissions capability. While stock Android allows you to control some permissions (such as camera or location access) for most apps, GrapheneOS allows you to control the sensors and network permissions as well. This network toggle in particular is a very powerful tool which can prevent any app you choose from connecting to the internet. This feature made me more comfortable installing some proprietary apps that I enjoy using but have no need for internet access. On stock Android, I have no choice but to allow them access anyway (and likely send data the app collects back to the developers) or else use an imperfect firewall solution like &lt;a href=&#34;https://netguard.me/&#34;&gt;Netguard&lt;/a&gt;. GrapheneOS lets me deny these apps network access on the operating system level, which is a far more ideal solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These permission toggles are available for Google Play Services as well, meaning you can decide exactly what permissions Google&amp;rsquo;s apps have on your phone even if you do choose to install them, which is simply impossible on stock Android. While this lessens some of the seamless experience of stock Android (I often have to manually approve requests for access from Google Play Services), the gain in privacy and security is definitely worth it. I can even install Google apps like GBoard on my phone and simply disallow them from using the internet, which they don&amp;rsquo;t need anyway. I even denied the network permission to the Google Play Store (I either download my apps manually or get them from F-Droid or Aurora Store) and found that app compatibility still works just fine. While the basic Google Play Services apps continue to have network access, I have still greatly limited the number of avenues Google has to siphon data from my phone, which feels really great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other security feature you may notice is &lt;a href=&#34;https://grapheneos.org/usage#exec-spawning&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;secure app spawning&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, which will cause a slight delay when opening apps. This delay is noticeable, but still quite short and it didn&amp;rsquo;t impact my usage of the phone at all. However, if you want to disable it, you can do so in the phone&amp;rsquo;s security settings and apps will open without the delay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34; &gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, I am quite happy with GrapheneOS. I did have to struggle a little bit with getting the sandboxed Google Play Services to work as I like, but at this point all the apps I need run smoothly and I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any compatibility issues. While GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; web installer is very easy to use, I still don&amp;rsquo;t think I can recommend the OS to my non-tech savvy friends and family. A fair bit of setup and tinkering with sandboxed Google Play Services was required for me to get it working smoothly and many of GrapheneOS&amp;rsquo; best security features would likely go unused and/or unappreciated, while the usability sacrifices would still be noticeable. For me personally however, GrapheneOS is a great fit and when I get my next phone, installing GrapheneOS on it will likely be the first thing I do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Basic Steps to Digital Privacy</title>
      <link>https://gunther.link/posts/privacy-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunther.link/posts/privacy-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34; &gt;Introduction
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though digital privacy is complex and achieving &amp;ldquo;complete&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;100%&amp;rdquo; privacy is virtually impossible, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean there aren&amp;rsquo;t simple steps you can take to improve. Most people&amp;rsquo;s digital privacy practices are pretty poor, which may be disheartening, but it also means that there is a lot of low-hanging fruit to be picked from the metaphorical digital privacy tree. Even if you have already put all of the steps I&amp;rsquo;m about to list into practice, consider sending this blog post to a friend or family member who may not have. And perhaps even digital privacy veterans will find one or two new ideas here. The following steps will go in order of those I consider to be relatively easy to actualize to ones I consider to be relatively difficult, but they should all be accessible to the technological layman. Additionally, this list focuses more on digital privacy than digital security and while the two often go hand-in-hand, your threat model may require you to focus more on security than privacy. Make sure to take your personal needs into account and fact check the information here before blindly following it. That said, I hope you find it useful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-change-your-web-browser&#34; &gt;1. Change Your Web Browser
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-change-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like most people, statistically, you are using Google Chrome as your primary web browser. On top of the open-source Chromium browser base, Google adds a variety of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mercurynews.com/2019/06/21/google-chrome-has-become-surveillance-software-its-time-to-switch/&#34;&gt;what can only be described as spyware&lt;/a&gt; to track your every move on the web. Every website you visit and likely much more is meticulously logged and recorded by Google so they can use the data to target or &amp;ldquo;personalize&amp;rdquo; ads toward you. The good news is that there are plenty of privacy-respecting alternatives to Google Chrome. The two easiest desktop browsers to recommend are the &lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34;&gt;Brave Browser&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&#34;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. Both are miles ahead of Google Chrome in terms of privacy and also very user-friendly. &lt;a href=&#34;https://privacytests.org/&#34;&gt;Brave is the more private by default&lt;/a&gt; and includes a built-in ad and tracker blocker. However, it also includes the somewhat annoying integration of its &lt;a href=&#34;https://basicattentiontoken.org/&#34;&gt;BAT cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;, though this can be disabled. If you want a browser that can just be downloaded and used relatively privately as-is, Brave is not a bad choice. If you&amp;rsquo;re willing to play with the settings, however, Firefox can become a powerfully private browser (using &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/arkenfox/user.js&#34;&gt;Arkenfox&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to achieve this). There are other private browsers out there as well, though Brave and Firefox are the simplest to recommend as drop-in Chrome alternatives. If you want to look into other options a bit more deeply, &lt;a href=&#34;https://unixsheikh.com/articles/choose-your-browser-carefully.html&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; is not a bad place to start. The mobile browser landscape is a bit more complex than desktop browsers&amp;rsquo;, but I would still continue to recommend Firefox and Brave as solid, private options for both iOS and Android (they are both certainly a step up from Chrome).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-switch-up-your-search-engine&#34; &gt;2. Switch Up Your Search Engine
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-switch-up-your-search-engine&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even though you&amp;rsquo;ve changed your web browser, you are still, statistically, using Google as your search engine and this needs to change. Google of course records every search you make regardless of whether or not you use their browser. While Chrome&amp;rsquo;s more private competitors are just as good as (if not better) than Chrome, the same can&amp;rsquo;t quite be said for private Google search alternatives. While many of them are quite good, none of them are &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as feature-rich and intuitive as Google is, and their search results are often lower quality. Nonetheless, the drop in usability is relatively minor and a worthwhile price to pay for the privacy to be gained. The most commonly recommended private alternative to Google Search is &lt;a href=&#34;https://duckduckgo.com/&#34;&gt;DuckDuckGo&lt;/a&gt;, which is not a bad search engine by any means, though its results (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DuckDuckGo&#34;&gt;mostly sourced from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Bing&lt;/a&gt;), are often not quite as good as Google&amp;rsquo;s. If you want privately proxied Google results, then &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.startpage.com/en/&#34;&gt;StartPage&lt;/a&gt; is a great option, since they simply pull from Google&amp;rsquo;s results and pass them on to you without Google&amp;rsquo;s personalization and tracking, but also without some of Google&amp;rsquo;s fancier features. &lt;a href=&#34;https://search.brave.com/&#34;&gt;Brave Search&lt;/a&gt; is also notable for having its own search index (rather than pulling from Google or Bing as Startpage and DuckDuckGo do) and its search results aren&amp;rsquo;t half-bad, though not quite on par with Google&amp;rsquo;s. There are other private alternatives as well (the self-hostable &lt;a href=&#34;https://searx.space/&#34;&gt;Searx&lt;/a&gt; certainly deserves a mention), but any of the initial 3 I mentioned should serve just fine as a private Google search alternative. Feel free to try a few and use the one you like most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-use-a-password-manager&#34; &gt;3. Use a Password Manager
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-use-a-password-manager&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using the same, easy-to-remember password for every online account you have is easy, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a terrible idea. It&amp;rsquo;s not a matter of &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; a service you use will get breached, but &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; (check &lt;a href=&#34;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&#34;&gt;haveibeenpwned.com&lt;/a&gt; to see if your information was already leaked). The most viable solution to this is to use a strong (preferably randomized) and unique password for each of your accounts. The only way to have access to all these different passwords while storing them securely is to use a password manager. A dedicated password manager is far more secure than writing the password down or storing them in a spreadsheet and is even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/447345/why-you-shouldnt-use-your-web-browsers-password-manager/&#34;&gt;more secure than using the in-browser password manager&lt;/a&gt;. There are a lot of password managers out there and using almost any of the well-known ones is better than using the same password everywhere, but the two generally best options are &lt;a href=&#34;https://bitwarden.com/&#34;&gt;Bitwarden&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://keepassxc.org/&#34;&gt;KeePassXC&lt;/a&gt;. Bitwarden is a cloud-based solution and is probably more convenient for most people, while KeePassXC will store your passwords encrypted on your desktop. Both of these password managers also have the ability to generate strong, random passwords for you as well as browser extensions which automatically fill those passwords into the login pages of each website you visit. While transitioning to using a password manager can be difficult at first, it will make your life much easier once you get used to it, and make your online accounts much safer as well! To further secure your online accounts, you may also want to consider adding &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication&#34;&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt; to the accounts that support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-get-a-better-messenger&#34; &gt;4. Get a Better Messenger
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#4-get-a-better-messenger&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Messages between our friends and family contain some of the most sensitive information about our personal lives, so it is important to choose a private and secure tool for sending and receiving those messages. SMS in an unencrypted protocol and your SMS messages can easily be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.howtogeek.com/709373/why-sms-text-messages-arent-private-or-secure/&#34;&gt;read by your cell service provider&lt;/a&gt; or by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://krebsonsecurity.com/2021/03/can-we-stop-pretending-sms-is-secure-now/&#34;&gt;intercepted by a bad actor&lt;/a&gt;. Some proprietary messengers, such as WhatsApp and iMessage are end-to-end encrypted by default, which means that only the sender and receiver of a message can read its contents. However, these services can use the metadata of your conversations (such as who you message and when) to build your advertising profile. Additionally, both WhatsApp and iMessage back up all your messages unencrypted to the cloud (either Google Drive or iCloud) by default, undermining much of the privacy provided by their end-to-end encryption. While there are a few options out there for private and secure messengers, the easiest to recommend by far is &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/en/&#34;&gt;Signal&lt;/a&gt;. Signal&amp;rsquo;s features are on par with competing messenger apps and its privacy and security are top-notch as well. It&amp;rsquo;s also free to use. While Signal may not be perfect (it requires a phone number to register and is a centralized service), it is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Signal_(software)#Security&#34;&gt;extremely well-vetted in terms of its security&lt;/a&gt; and in addition to being end-to-end encrypted by default, &lt;a href=&#34;https://signal.org/bigbrother/&#34;&gt;stores close to zero metadata on its users&lt;/a&gt;. While there are other private messaging options out there like &lt;a href=&#34;https://getsession.org/&#34;&gt;Session&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://threema.ch/en&#34;&gt;Threema&lt;/a&gt;, Signal strikes the best balance between privacy, security, and usability. Usability is far more important for a messenger than it is for a browser or search engine, since not only do you have to be convinced that the privacy and security gains are worth any usability losses, but you have to convince your friends and family too or you won&amp;rsquo;t have anyone to message with!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-minimize-and-scrutinize-apps-and-browser-extensions&#34; &gt;5. Minimize and Scrutinize Apps and Browser Extensions
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#5-minimize-and-scrutinize-apps-and-browser-extensions&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every program you install on your computer, every app you install on your phone, and every extension you install in your browser is a potential security and privacy risk. These programs, apps, and extensions all have privileged access to your device and a compromised device can undo any progress you have made in your digital privacy by sending your personal data directly to bad actors. Even if the app or extension is not inherently malicious, it can provide an attack surface that can be exploited by malware. A simple step you can take to greatly mitigate this risk is to be very selective when installing computer programs, apps, and extensions. The fewer you have, the lower the chances that one of them will be turned into a backdoor into your device. Many mobile apps and PC programs can be replaced with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pcmag.com/how-to/how-to-use-progressive-web-apps&#34;&gt;progressive web application&lt;/a&gt;, which is essentially a browser shortcut icon on your phone or desktop homescreen that can provide much of the same functionality as a fully-fledged application with significantly less of a security risk since it runs through your browser rather than as an independent program. While many browser extensions can be deleted without losing much, you should strongly consider using a tracker-blocking extension like &lt;a href=&#34;https://ublockorigin.com/&#34;&gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt;. For the remaining programs and apps that you do need, consider looking for an open-source alternative to the more likely more popular proprietary options. While open source software isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily guaranteed to be any more private and secure, developers who make privacy-friendly software tend to make that software open source so that the source code can be reviewed and shown to be as privacy-friendly as its developers claim. All of the programs that have been suggested in this guide so far, like Firefox and Signal, are open source software!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-sign-up-for-a-privacy-respecting-email-service&#34; &gt;6. Sign Up for a Privacy-Respecting Email Service
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#6-sign-up-for-a-privacy-respecting-email-service&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The email protocol is relatively old and not very secure or private by design, but virtually everyone nowadays needs an email address. So while all of your personal and sensitive communications should go through a private and secure messenger like Signal, using a privacy-friendly email provider is still an important step toward digital privacy. Email providers like Gmail can and do &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jun/26/google-will-stop-scanning-content-of-personal-emails&#34;&gt;read your emails and use their metadata to build your advertising profile&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an in-depth discussion of different privacy-respecting email providers, you should check out &lt;a href=&#34;https://gunther.link/posts/email/&#34;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt;. In short however, the easiest free, drop-in replacement for Gmail I can recommend is &lt;a href=&#34;https://proton.me/mail&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-eschew-iot-devices&#34; &gt;7. Eschew IoT Devices
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#7-eschew-iot-devices&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;internet of things&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; describes the growing number of household devices that can be connected to the internet. Once upon a time, only desktop computers were able to connect. Then, our cell phones graduated to &amp;ldquo;smart phones&amp;rdquo; with internet connectivity. Nowadays, almost every personal and household device has a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; version. Smart TVs, smart thermostats, smart watches, smart vacuums, smart beds, smart doorbells, and smart refrigerators, in addition to home media centers, video game consoles, and ebooks, just to name a few. But the internet of things is not good for your privacy. It is an open secret that companies use these devices to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2022/jan/29/what-your-smart-tv-knows-about-you-and-how-to-stop-it-harvesting-data&#34;&gt;spy on their users&lt;/a&gt;, gathering more personal data for their advertising profiles. IoT devices often have weak security and can be prime targets for cybercriminals looking to &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.radware.com/uncategorized/2018/03/history-of-iot-botnets/&#34;&gt;build botnets&lt;/a&gt; or gain a foothold in your home network. To top it off, many of these &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; devices don&amp;rsquo;t even provide much utility beyond the device&amp;rsquo;s basic, offline functions anyway. Consider buying devices and gadgets that do not connect to the internet and if you do buy a smart device, consider leaving it offline. If you do require an IoT device, make sure to change any default security credentials and to opt out of any analytics and tracking that you can in the device or account settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-limit-social-media-usage&#34; &gt;8. Limit Social Media Usage
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#8-limit-social-media-usage&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social media is a ubiquitous part of modern life, but in addition to its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4183915/&#34;&gt;deleterious effects on mental health&lt;/a&gt;, it is also bad for privacy. Social media companies are some of the most privacy-violating and Facebook (which also owns Instagram), is particularly infamous for its &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techrepublic.com/article/facebook-data-privacy-scandal-a-cheat-sheet/&#34;&gt;invasive data collection from its users&lt;/a&gt;. But even if social media companies didn&amp;rsquo;t so nakedly violate their users&amp;rsquo; privacy, most social media sites center around posting your personal information on the public internet and trying to get as many people to see and interact with it as possible! The best advice to prevent this is to simply delete your social media profiles altogether, though this is impractical for many of us for either social or professional reasons. If you do decide to keep your social media accounts, make sure you&amp;rsquo;re not leaking any more private information than you need to. Consider deleting social media apps from your phone and only accessing the services via your browser (this is good for preventing late-night doomscrolling as well). Go through your accounts&amp;rsquo; privacy settings and make sure your information isn&amp;rsquo;t being shared more widely than it needs to be (checking your account privacy settings is also a good idea for your other privacy-invasive services you may have as well, like Google). Finally, think carefully before posting information or adding information to your social media profiles. Make sure the information really needs to be there and check whether it contains any personal details you would prefer to not be public knowledge. You may also want to consider using social media pseudonymously where possible. While keeping your real-life identity and a social media pseudonym completely disconnected can be quite difficult, that&amp;rsquo;s no reason to add more personal information about yourself that will show up with a simple internet search of your real name. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fediverse&#34;&gt;The Fediverse&lt;/a&gt; can also be a good alternative to proprietary social media services since many instances of fediverse platforms are open source and relatively privacy-respecting, but even these upsides don&amp;rsquo;t change the need to be cautious with what information you post!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-change-your-dns-provider-andor-use-a-vpn&#34; &gt;9. Change Your DNS Provider and/or Use a VPN
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#9-change-your-dns-provider-andor-use-a-vpn&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, your ISP is another company that is likely &lt;a href=&#34;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2017/03/senate-votes-to-let-isps-sell-your-web-browsing-history-to-advertisers/&#34;&gt;mining your internet activity to sell to data brokers&lt;/a&gt;. However, there are some simple steps you can take to mitigate this risk. Firstly, you can change your DNS provider. DNS is the protocol by which domain names (like example.com) are translated to IP addresses, which computers use to connect to other servers. By default, you are likely using your ISP&amp;rsquo;s default DNS resolver, but you can do better. Go into your internet router&amp;rsquo;s settings and change the DNS resolver servers to a more private provider like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quad9.net/&#34;&gt;Quad9&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://adguard-dns.io/en/public-dns.html&#34;&gt;AdGuard&lt;/a&gt;. Both of these DNS resolvers block domains associated with malware and AdGuard blocks domains associated with advertisements and tracking as well. In addition to changing your DNS resolver in your router settings, you can also change it in your PC or phone device settings or in your browser settings. This has the advantage of working even when not connected to your home network and can take advantage of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/dns/dns-over-tls/&#34;&gt;encrypted DNS lookup protocols&lt;/a&gt;. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to set up a custom ruleset for your DNS resolver to block any domain you&amp;rsquo;d like, &lt;a href=&#34;https://adguard-dns.io/en/welcome.html&#34;&gt;Adguard can do that for you&lt;/a&gt; and so can &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextdns.io/&#34;&gt;NextDNS&lt;/a&gt;. Of course, hiding your DNS queries from your ISP still allows them to see every IP address you connect to. This can be prevented by using a trustworthy VPN provider. Many VPN providers will claim a variety of benefits that come from using a VPN but these are often exaggerated and the main privacy benefits are (1) hiding the servers you connect to from your ISP and (2) hiding your own IP address from the servers you connect to. Of course, by using a VPN service to achieve these goals, you are simply shifting your trust from your ISP to the VPN provider, so make sure the VPN provider you use is trustworthy! Almost all free VPNs, and even many paid VPNs, are collecting and selling your data. The most-trusted VPN services as of this writing are &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonvpn.com/&#34;&gt;ProtonVPN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mullvad.net/en/&#34;&gt;MullVad&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ivpn.net/&#34;&gt;IVPN&lt;/a&gt;. There are a few free and trustworthy VPN options, such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://protonvpn.com/plans/&#34;&gt;ProtonVPN&amp;rsquo;s free tier&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://riseup.net/en/vpn&#34;&gt;RiseUp VPN&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calyx.net/&#34;&gt;CalyxVPN&lt;/a&gt;, but these often have throttled speeds and as a general rule you should expect to pay for a trustworthy VPN service. Another free option that provides the privacy benefits of a VPN (and a lot more as well) is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/download/&#34;&gt;Tor Browser&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike VPNs, the Tor Browser &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techradar.com/vpn/what-is-tor-and-how-does-it-work&#34;&gt;distributes trust amongst multiple third parties&lt;/a&gt; and does its best to allow you to browse the web anonymously. However, your browsing speeds using Tor will be quite slow compared to using a standard web browser with a quality VPN, so it may not always be the best solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-remove-your-data-from-people-search-sites&#34; &gt;10. Remove Your Data from People-Search Sites
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#10-remove-your-data-from-people-search-sites&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Believe it or not, there are many sites out there which are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2017/3/21/14945884/people-search-sites-history-privacy-regulation&#34;&gt;designed just to collect information about you and sell it to anyone interested&lt;/a&gt;. Creepy, right? Well, luckily many of these sites have the option to opt-out and remove your data from the site, but this is a slow and arduous process by design. The potential upside of removing this (sometimes very invasive) data about yourself from the web is high, but will require significant amounts of either your time or money to achieve, which is why it is the last step on this list. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to request removal of your information from each of these sites manually, you can find a pretty good guide for doing that &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yaelwrites/Big-Ass-Data-Broker-Opt-Out-List&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There are also paid services which will do this grueling task for you like &lt;a href=&#34;https://joindeleteme.com/&#34;&gt;DeleteMe&lt;/a&gt; (some other paid services are reviewed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://yewtu.be/watch?v=ts6fqahljPE&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34; &gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is hardly an exhaustive list of steps that can be taken to improve your digital privacy, but the steps that are listed should be relatively accessible to a wide audience and have a large positive impact in proportion to how much effort they require. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to learn more about how to improve your digital privacy, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.privacyguides.org/&#34;&gt;Privacy Guides&lt;/a&gt; is probably the best online resource currently out there, but it&amp;rsquo;s certainly not the only one! I hope the steps I have listed here will help at least a few people start working toward making their digital lives a bit more private as big tech companies work tirelessly to make sure they are anything but.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Opacity and the Cause of Consumer Indifference</title>
      <link>https://gunther.link/posts/tracking_opacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunther.link/posts/tracking_opacity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People who care about privacy online are often frustrated by the inability of the masses, often including their friends and family, to see the importance of using privacy-preserving online services. But companies like Google and Facebook work very hard to make sure people reach the conclusion that online privacy simply isn&amp;rsquo;t that important. The first and most obvious way they do this is by offering genuinely good services. Millions if not billions of dollars are used to develop Google&amp;rsquo;s and Facebook&amp;rsquo;s products to make them as seamless and user-friendly as possible. A FOSS, privacy-preserving alternative to Gmail for example, will often have trouble raising even a fraction of the funds available to Gmail to develop their product. While some dedicated and talented developers can make up for some of the lack of funding, even FOSS developers need to eat and they are competing against Google&amp;rsquo;s engineers and developers, who are well-paid, well-organized, and well-funded. Meanwhile, Google funds its services from selling its users&amp;rsquo; data, meaning it can offer these services to them at no (monetary) cost. The FOSS developer has to therefore find a way to fund their project without charging the user at risk of being even a less attractive alternative to Google. Sure, they can proudly claim that they don&amp;rsquo;t sell user data, but to the average user, that&amp;rsquo;s likely not enough of a reason to sacrifice features and usability and perhaps having to pay a fee to boot. Many privacy-preserving FOSS products and services overcome these challenges and manage to use innovative monetization to build a niche market for themselves, but these are relatively few and far-between and are constantly fighting an uphill battle in an attempt to compete with big tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big companies also rely heavily on the network effect. How can a FOSS, privacy-preserving messenger beat out WhatsApp or iMessage when choosing the alternative messaging service will mean being unable communicate with the vast majority of people who still use the mainstream services? The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/XMPP#Decentralization&#34;&gt;decentralized nature of something like XMPP&lt;/a&gt; is certainly more the exception than the rule when it comes to modern messengers and even an open-source, private messenger like Signal locks its users into using its servers to communicate. Google&amp;rsquo;s integration into Android devices is another permutation of the same principle. Why should a user bother looking for a different cloud storage provider or local backup solution that they will then have to configure when Google Drive is already integrated with their Android device, no setup required?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So convenience and price are clearly big motivators when it comes to why people ignore the privacy-invasive practices of big tech. But perhaps the most common reason people give is that they simply don&amp;rsquo;t care. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2010/jan/11/facebook-privacy&#34;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg infamously said in 2010 that &amp;ldquo;privacy is no longer a social norm.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; And many people are quick to agree. &amp;ldquo;I have nothing to hide.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to be private nowadays anyway.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t really care if Google reads my search history.&amp;rdquo; These are refrains familiar to anyone who has tried to convince their friends and family of the value of digital privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I would argue that most people do care about their privacy. Claiming they do not is only possible because of the siren song of convenient services that big tech offers and the ignorance of what digital privacy really means. One of the strongest weapons that Google and other surveillance companies have in their arsenal is tracking opacity, the opposite of transparency. My impression is that most people are aware that Google stores and sells their &amp;ldquo;data,&amp;rdquo; but very few people have a concrete idea of what that means. And that is just how Google likes it. It is very easy to use Google services and forget that they are observing everything you do. They don&amp;rsquo;t announce it, it happens silently. Even when you open Google Maps and see a list of all of the locations you previously searched for, it is easy to see that information as only available to you. It is only available on your device after all, or only when logged into your account. Google never openly &lt;em&gt;claims&lt;/em&gt; that this information is only available to you, but it works very hard to make you &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; that way. In the early days of tech, almost all of our personal data was stored locally. This very much habituated us to the idea that only we had access to our data. In the decades since, almost everything has moved to the cloud, but our mindsets have not changed. The obvious differences between writing a digital diary on Microsoft Word in 1995 and on Google Docs in 2022 are the better features Google Drive provides and the convenience of being able to access the file on almost any device. The fact that in 2022 the data is stored on Google&amp;rsquo;s servers where they are freely able to do what they wish with it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come to mind. giving its users the illusion of data sovereignty is very much a deliberate design choice on Google&amp;rsquo;s part.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracking opacity generally manifests in two ways: (1) opacity of what data is collected and (2) opacity of how that data is used. Most people don&amp;rsquo;t realize that their &lt;a href=&#34;https://qz.com/1131515/google-collects-android-users-locations-even-when-location-services-are-disabled/&#34;&gt;Android phones are nearly constantly sending their physical location to Google&lt;/a&gt; because Google makes it very difficult to see that they are in fact doing that. Occasionally, Google or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lane_v._Facebook,_Inc.&#34;&gt;Facebook will slip up and reveal to their users just how invasive their tracking is&lt;/a&gt;, but at any hint of outcry, they will &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnbc.com/2018/04/04/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-user-privacy-issues-my-mistake.html&#34;&gt;claim it was a &amp;ldquo;mistake&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and make &lt;a href=&#34;https://apnews.com/article/828aefab64d4411bac257a07c1af0ecb&#34;&gt;superficial changes which make the tracking harder to see without actually getting rid of it&lt;/a&gt;. Even if you do realize that your location data is being sent to Google, you have no idea what its being used for. Google and other companies make sure to have long terms of service agreements and privacy policies filled with legalese that most people will not have the time or energy to read and would not be able to understand even if they did. Even after reading and understanding these policies, the exact way Google uses to data is still incredibly vague. Phrases like &amp;ldquo;improve services&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;shared with our partners&amp;rdquo; are extremely general and tells the user almost nothing about what their data will actually be used for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it any wonder that so many people claim to not care about their privacy when companies like Google make it so hard to understand what data is being collected and how it&amp;rsquo;s used? As long as this is unclear, people have plausible deniability. Paranoid, privacy-conscious people will assume Google is collecting all the data it can and using it for whatever purposes make it the most money, while less paranoid people won&amp;rsquo;t pay the issue much mind at all. Google has specifically designed a system so that they don&amp;rsquo;t have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I have no real solutions to offer here. The best solution would likely be some sort of privacy transparency law which would require companies to simply, clearly, and explicitly outline what data is collected and how it is used. This would be far better than the current system of dense and opaque privacy policies which are designed to be impossible to understand and impossible to opt out of. Given big tech&amp;rsquo;s lobbying power, this is a far-fetched solution and would require real thought to implement properly in any event. Many FOSS projects do have simple and easy-to-read privacy policies, but perhaps some kind of standard short-hand for letting users know what data is collected and how it is used could be developed in the FOSS world? At the very least this could provide a template for any potential future data tracking transparency law to use. In the meantime though, we are stuck with using our best guess for how tech companies track us and use our data, which is just how they like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding a Privacy-Friendly Email Provider</title>
      <link>https://gunther.link/posts/email/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunther.link/posts/email/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: The following is my opinion based on personal experience and does not constitute expert advice or guidance. I am not sponsored by, supported by, or otherwise financially biased toward any of the services mentioned.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-problem-with-gmail&#34; &gt;The Problem with Gmail
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-problem-with-gmail&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like most people, I used to rely on Google heavily for basically all of the core online services I used. When I realized what an invasive and anti-privacy company Google is, it was pretty simple for me to ditch Google Chrome for one of the more privacy-friendly alternatives and switch my default search engine to something like DuckDuckGo. It took me much longer to start looking for a better email provider. Downloading a new browser and switching the default search engine is free, only takes a few minutes and the end result is a user experience that is about as good as Chrome+Google. Email is another beast entirely. Gmail&amp;rsquo;s features are really quite good and you can get a Gmail account for free. Well, for &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; I suppose, since you are paying with your data and your privacy. Google openly admits that it was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/jun/26/google-will-stop-scanning-content-of-personal-emails&#34;&gt;reading its&amp;rsquo; customers emails to build their ad profiles until 2017&lt;/a&gt; and even now there is really nothing stopping Google (or a rogue Google employee) from reading your emails if they wish. And you better believe that Gmail is still using all of your email metadata (like who you email and how often) to serve you more personalized ads regardless of whether or not they read the emails themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that privacy-friendly alternatives to Gmail are either paid, lacking features when compared to Gmail, or both. That being said, if you want to take your digital privacy seriously, Gmail and other free email providers like Yahoo! or Outlook are not real options so you will have to get comfortable with either paying for your email service with cash instead of with your data or with losing some of Gmail&amp;rsquo;s functionality. In my quest to find a Gmail alternative, I looked into quite a few different email providers and tried out 4 myself: ProtonMail, Tutanota, Mailbox.org, and Posteo. Most of the other providers I looked into were either not privacy-friendly, too expensive, or lacking sufficient reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;protonmail&#34; &gt;ProtonMail
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#protonmail&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://proton.me/mail&#34;&gt;ProtonMail&lt;/a&gt; is probably the first suggestion you will hear when asking for a privacy-friendly alternative to Gmail and with good reason. The service has been around for a while and has a good reputation (despite the more paranoid side of the digital privacy community insisting it&amp;rsquo;s a honeypot, most of the so-called &amp;ldquo;scandals&amp;rdquo; boil down to Proton turning over data to the authorities when required by local law). ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s interface is very user-friendly and is somewhat reminiscent of Gmail&amp;rsquo;s. ProtonMail also encrypts all emails by default using PGP (though see disclaimers below), while also providing the option for users to use their own PGP keys. ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s free tier is quite generous and includes 1 GB of storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the downsides. The main concern I had with ProtonMail was its pricing. While the free tier is very generous, it is restricted to only 150 messages per day (more than most personal accounts need, to be fair) and does not offer custom domain support, alias addresses, or IMAP support. IMAP support essentially allows you to use 3rd-party email clients and I personally consider it to be a pretty essential feature. I like having a copy of my emails stored on my local machine and I don&amp;rsquo;t like being locked in to my email provider&amp;rsquo;s email client. While I think it is perfectly fair to lock these features behind a paywall (they do need to make money after all), &lt;a href=&#34;https://proton.me/pricing?product=mail&#34;&gt;the lowest paid tier (as of this writing) is 4.99/month&lt;/a&gt;! While they do offer slight discounts for yearly/biyearly subscriptions, this is way too much to charge for an email service. I assume the high price is trying to push people toward the &amp;ldquo;Proton Unlimited&amp;rdquo; package, which also includes access to Proton&amp;rsquo;s VPN and cloud storage services. And while Proton Unlimited may be reasonably priced for what it offers, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t much help users who are &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; looking for an email service. Additionally, even with a paid plan, IMAP support is only offered through the ProtonMail Bridge. The Bridge is not available for mobile however, meaning you&amp;rsquo;re stuck with the ProtonMail client on Android/iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason why ProtonMail requires the Bridge in order to support IMAP is because ProtonMail end-to-end encrypts all of its messages by default. This is one of the major draws of ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s service from a privacy perspective, but is also not all that it&amp;rsquo;s cracked up to be. While ProtonMail does end-to-end encrypt all emails sent between ProtonMail accounts (as well as emails which are &amp;ldquo;at rest&amp;rdquo; on their servers), any emails sent to non-ProtonMail accounts are not encrypted by default while in transit. This is not ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s fault, but is a simple consequence of email&amp;rsquo;s decentralized nature. That being said, the idea of ProtonMail end-to-end encrypting all emails by default loses a lot of its appeal when you realize that &amp;ldquo;all&amp;rdquo; really only includes a small percentage of the emails most people will be sending/receiving. While ProtonMail does offer PGP support to encrypt emails sent to other servers, PGP support has been a standard feature of basically any email client worth discussing for a long time now and supporting it hardly makes ProtonMail unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all that being said, ProtonMail is still a very good option as a Gmail alternative. Its free tier is great if you want a semi-disposable account or if you have modest needs from your email provider. While I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend the expensive, mail-only paid tier, if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in going all-in on Proton&amp;rsquo;s larger ecosystem, Proton Unlimited could be a really good option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tutanota&#34; &gt;Tutanota
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#tutanota&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tutanota.com/&#34;&gt;Tutanota&lt;/a&gt; is probably the most well-known privacy-friendly email provider after ProtonMail. Like ProtonMail, they place their emphasis on end-to-end encryption and open-source in their attempt to build a trustworthy and privacy-friendly email platform. Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s encryption is very robust and &lt;a href=&#34;https://tutanota.com/blog/posts/innovative-encryption&#34;&gt;has some advantages over ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s and over PGP in general&lt;/a&gt;. Tutanota also offers a free plan, which while not as generous as ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s, is pretty decent and is likely serviceable for many users. It includes 1 GB of storage while paywalling features like email aliases and custom domain support. The other feature that is paywalled is &amp;ldquo;unlimited search.&amp;rdquo; Essentially, Tutanota allows free users to only search for recent emails. Older emails will have to be found manually and not using the search function. While this does seem like a pretty basic feature to keep paywalled, I suppose they need something to push users toward paid plans, so I can&amp;rsquo;t really blame them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike ProtonMail, Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s lowest paid tier is priced at a reasonable &lt;a href=&#34;https://tutanota.com/pricing&#34;&gt;1.20/month (or 1/month for a yearly plan)&lt;/a&gt; and includes unlimited search, custom domain support and 5 aliases. Other features such as extra email aliases and extra storage are offered  la carte. The major feature that is missing from both Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s free and paid plans is IMAP support, meaning you are locked in to Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s (open source) email clients. Like ProtonMail, the reasoning for this is Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s encryption implementation. Unlike ProtonMail however, Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s email client is pretty basic. Honestly, it worked just fine for my needs, but it is relatively feature-poor and has a few unintuitive UI choices which could alienate some users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also like ProtonMail, Tutanota end-to-end encrypts emails between Tutanota accounts by default, but this comes with many of the same caveats. Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s end-to-end encryption will not work for external email address unless you set a password for the email message. This is cumbersome to do and poses the problem of how to securely share the password to the email recipient. You could send it over a secure messenger like Signal, but if you already have a secure communication channel, why would you need Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s password-encrypted emails? PGP solves this problem by using public/private key pairs, and while Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s encryption is stronger than PGP&amp;rsquo;s (they claim it&amp;rsquo;s quantum-resistant) and encrypts metadata like the subject line (which PGP does not), its benefits don&amp;rsquo;t really seem to outweigh the downside of abandoning public/private key pairs for a password. Not only that, but you have no option to integrate PGP with Tutanota even if you want to, meaning that you are stuck using their encryption or nothing (I suppose you could encrypt the message yourself and then put the encrypted text in the email, but that seems like a lot of extra work). While you can of course just insist that any correspondents also use a Tutanota account, a program like Signal seems a lot more suited to that use case since one of the major advantages of email is its wide adoption decentralized nature. &lt;a href=&#34;https://proton.me/support/password-protected-emails&#34;&gt;ProtonMail also offers password-protected emails&lt;/a&gt; and many of these points apply to ProtonMail as well, but they at least give you option of using desktop email clients and/or your own PGP keys, so these problems are all the more glaring with Tutanota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its shortcomings, Tutanota still has a strong use case. I could particularly imagine its end-to-end encryption implementation being put to good use in a team setting where there would be a lot of sensitive, internal email communications. If you are aware of and comfortable with Tutanota&amp;rsquo;s shortcomings, its paid tier is reasonably priced and not a bad option overall and its free tier is a slightly inferior but still noteworthy alternative to ProtonMail&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mailboxorg&#34; &gt;Mailbox.org
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#mailboxorg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While not as well-known as ProtonMail and Tutanota, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailbox.org/en/&#34;&gt;Mailbox.org&lt;/a&gt; is another common name you&amp;rsquo;ll hear tossed around when privacy-friendly email services are discussed. Mailbox.org doesn&amp;rsquo;t claim to end-to-end encrypt all its emails like ProtonMail and Tutanota do, but instead offers a more &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; email functionality free of the mailbox snooping and analytics shenanigans Google is known for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most underrated advantages of Mailbox.org is the fact that it has normal name. While this may sound like a silly consideration, if you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to read out your email address to a customer service representative on the phone or a casual acquaintance in real life, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that having an email address like coolguy69&lt;span&gt;@cock.&lt;/span&gt;haha may have seemed like a great idea when you were just typing it online but suddenly becomes a bit of an embarrassment. Even a relatively more normal email address like yourname&lt;span&gt;@tutanota.&lt;/span&gt;com
can earn you weird looks and questions like &amp;ldquo;how do you spell that?&amp;rdquo; when trying to do something simple like share your email address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of features, Mailbox.org is nothing special but does everything you could reasonably want an email provider to do. Its webmail client is perfectly functional and IMAP support is an included feature with all plans so you&amp;rsquo;re not forced to use it anyway. Mailbox.org also claims to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailbox.org/en/company#our-responsibility&#34;&gt;fully powered by green energy&lt;/a&gt;. It is nice to see services like Mailbox.org that seem committed to social progress generally beyond the narrow (though important) area of digital privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One point of note about Mailbox.org that may be a dealbreaker for some is that it has no free tier. However, if you already planned on paying cash for your email provider, &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailbox.org/en/services&#34;&gt;Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s plans start at 1/month&lt;/a&gt;, which is quite competitive. Although you can only credit your account with a minimum of 12, they do offer refund options if you with to cancel your account before you&amp;rsquo;ve used up your balance. The lowest tier includes 3 email alises and 2 GB of storage. The higher tiers (3/month and 9/month) offer more storage and aliases, custom domain support, as well as cloud storage and an office suite if that&amp;rsquo;s something you&amp;rsquo;d want from your email provider. In my opinion, everything but the lowest tier is overpriced and its a shame that custom domain support is not available on the lowest tier. The custom domain support and 25 alias addresses in addition to disposable email addresses do make the 3/month tier somewhat attractive, but it&amp;rsquo;s still a bit much to pay for an email service in my opinion, especially since there&amp;rsquo;s no option to purchase these features separately  la carte like there is with Tutanota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major concerns I had with Mailbox.org related to security and usability rather than to price. When I went to enable TOTP 2FA on my account, I found that I needed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/en/private/account-article/how-to-use-two-factor-authentication-2fa&#34;&gt;set a PIN and that I would then enter that PIN followed by the TOTP code into the password box in lieu of my password&lt;/a&gt;. This seems totally ridiculous to me. What&amp;rsquo;s the point of 2FA when you&amp;rsquo;re basically decimating the security of one of the factors by reducing its complexity to a numeric PIN? I ended up feeling more comfortable leaving 2FA off and simply using my randomly generated password. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen TOTP 2FA implemented this way before and it did not instill a ton of confidence in Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second security-related concern I had was with Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s encryption implementation. Mailbox.org doesn&amp;rsquo;t claim to end-to-end encrypt all of the emails it sends like ProtonMail and Tutanota do, which is fine from my perspective. As I discussed above, the end-to-end encrypted email claim comes with a lot of caveats anyway. That being said, my emails being encrypted while at rest on my provider&amp;rsquo;s servers is a worthwhile feature and doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact email&amp;rsquo;s usability as a decentralized service. Mailbox.org doesn&amp;rsquo;t do this by default and finding the setting was a real pain. In general, while Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s webmail client is perfectly serviceable, its settings panel is a huge mess and its documentation doesn&amp;rsquo;t do a ton to help out. Eventually I did find the setting to encrypt emails at rest, which required &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/en/private/e-mail-article/your-encrypted-mailbox&#34;&gt;inputting a public PGP key to encrypt the emails with&lt;/a&gt;. While I guess this is fine, I would have really preferred a toggle where I could simply encrypt my at-rest emails using my password. There was also a totally separate setting called &lt;a href=&#34;https://kb.mailbox.org/en/private/e-mail-article/send-encrypted-e-mails-with-guard&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;mailbox.org Guard,&amp;rdquo; which seems to be used to encrypt emails sent from the account&lt;/a&gt;, but the functionality seemed a little overlapping and finding the proper documentation explaining what each setting was for was a bit of a pain. Even now, I&amp;rsquo;m a little unsure how to implement each of these features and how they overlap. I suppose this is more of a usability concern than a security concern, but it was still disheartening to see what should be a core security feature made so opaque and complicated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mailbox.org certainly gets points for its relative simplicity and IMAP support even on its cheapest plans. However, some of its security practices certainly seem like red flags (or at least yellow flags) to me and so I&amp;rsquo;m afraid I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend the service in confidence. If you&amp;rsquo;re not looking for anything fancy security-wise and just want a simple email provider who won&amp;rsquo;t mine your data (and has a normal-sounding domain name to boot) or need both IMAP and custom domain support and don&amp;rsquo;t mind paying a little extra, perhaps Mailbox.org is worth looking into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;posteo&#34; &gt;Posteo
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#posteo&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en&#34;&gt;Posteo&lt;/a&gt; is probably the email service on this list which I hear about the least and it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a hidden gem in my opinion. I first heard about it from &lt;a href=&#34;https://digdeeper.neocities.org/ghost/email.html&#34;&gt;DigDeeper&amp;rsquo;s article on choosing an email provider&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m a little hesitant to reference the article here since the author is a bit of a conspiracy nut, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t found a comparable overview of email providers from a privacy standpoint that has the same breadth and depth. DigDeeper actually seems to have bothered reading (or at least skimming) the privacy policy and terms of service for each provider they reviewed. If you give the article a look though, make sure to take the author&amp;rsquo;s claims of what qualifies an email provider as and disqualifies it from being private and secure with a few grains of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posteo is very similar to Mailbox.org on its surface. Both services are hosted in Germany (as is Tutanota, by the way), both lack free tiers but offer subscriptions with IMAP support from as low as 1/month, and both have similar-looking, green-colored web interfaces and &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/site/sustainability&#34;&gt;use green energy&lt;/a&gt;. Part of me suspects that one project was a breakaway from the other, but I have no proof of that either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what makes Posteo unique? Well, Posteo properly implements TOTP 2FA for one thing. Even with 2FA enabled, IMAP is still accessible with your password alone (this is more of an IMAP limitation than a Posteo limitation as best as I can tell), but you do have the option to turn off IMAP access for your account if you wish. The settings in general are also much simpler to navigate than Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s (even I did stumble across a German phrase here or there where English probably should have been). While Posteo does not offer end-to-end encryption by default between Posteo users like ProtonMail and Tutanota, they do have &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/help/how-do-i-activate-posteo-crypto-mail-storage&#34;&gt;a simple option for encrypting your emails at rest with your password&lt;/a&gt; and they also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/help/how-do-i-activate-inbound-encryption-with-my-public-pgp-key&#34;&gt;support for encrypting them with your public PGP key&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d prefer. While the encryption is disabled by default, this is somewhat understandable since enabling the encryption prevents you from being able to recover your previous emails if you lose your password, which might not be something the average user wants. But it is good that it&amp;rsquo;s there and good that it&amp;rsquo;s pretty simple to activate. There is also the option of &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/help/activating-tls-sending-guarantee&#34;&gt;mandating TLS for sent&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/help/activate-tls-receiving-guarantee&#34;&gt;received&lt;/a&gt; emails (not sure how useful this actually is, but it&amp;rsquo;s an option if you want it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posteo&amp;rsquo;s pricing consists of a single tier costing 1/month for basic email access with IMAP support, 2 GB of storage and 2 alias addresses included. You can pay extra for additional alias addresses (0.10/address) or storage space. While all of the providers on this list accept some form of anonymous payment (either cash by mail, cryptocurrency or both), Posteo is the only one that I noticed claimed that your payment info will be kept anonymous from your account if you choose to pay by credit card. Not sure how realistic that claim is, so make what you will of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s not to like? The biggest shortcoming is a lack of support for custom domains. Posteo claims that this is because &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/site/faq&#34;&gt;allowing custom domains would sacrifice their users&amp;rsquo; privacy&lt;/a&gt;, but if that is really the reason, I don&amp;rsquo;t see why they make that decision unilaterally instead of letting their users decide. Additionally, aliases are capped at 20 per account. This is admittedly more than most people need, but it&amp;rsquo;s curious why they would put a cap on alias addresses per account at all if you pay for each one. And while Posteo does have &lt;a href=&#34;https://posteo.de/en/help/which-domains-are-available-to-use-as-a-posteo-alias-address&#34;&gt;a variety of domains available for their aliases&lt;/a&gt;, there is no .com option (though they do have .org and .net). Finally, their webmail interface works just fine but is nothing special, though this is a moot point if you&amp;rsquo;re planning to use an IMAP-based email client anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Posteo is a great choice overall and probably the best, cheap option if IMAP support is a must for you as it is for me. It is basically superior to Mailbox.org&amp;rsquo;s lowest tier in every conceivable way (other than the domain name, I suppose) and has quite a few advantages over ProtonMail and Tutanota as well, even if the overall advantage there isn&amp;rsquo;t clear-cut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34; &gt;Conclusion
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#conclusion&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s really no &amp;ldquo;gold standard&amp;rdquo; for a privacy-respecting email service at this point. Each service I looked into was lacking in some way. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that there are no good options though, just that you will have to make some sacrifices in either price or features to find a privacy-respecting email provider that works for you. I ultimately decided to go with Posteo as I felt it had the best balance of price and features. I did seriously consider Tutanota as well, but its lack of IMAP and PGP support didn&amp;rsquo;t overcome its other advantages (like custom domain support) for me. If I ever decide to sign up for Proton&amp;rsquo;s full suite of products I could perhaps see myself moving to ProtonMail, but the price of their email service alone is just too high for it to be a consideration for me at this point. I hope this provided some useful information if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a privacy-respecting email provider yourself (or perhaps encouraged you to start looking). Don&amp;rsquo;t rely on my conclusions though. Try out a few services, do your own research and don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to share your conclusions with others when you&amp;rsquo;re done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintendo Switch Ban Essentials: Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://gunther.link/posts/nxban/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gunther.link/posts/nxban/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: This guide has not been meaningfully updated since 2020 and may be out of date. Use at your own risk. A (more) updated version can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nx.eiphax.tech/ban&#34;&gt;Eip&amp;rsquo;s website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bans are scary and Nintendo hasnt been shy about banning hacked Switch consoles. However, educated hackers know that bans are avoidable and they know how to avoid them. The Q&amp;amp;A below should answer any questions you may have on how bans work and how to avoid getting your console banned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any further questions after reading this page, you can ask them on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/C29hYvh&#34;&gt;Nintendo Homebrew Discord server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-is-a-ban-and-how-does-it-happen&#34; &gt;1. What is a ban and how does it happen?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#1-what-is-a-ban-and-how-does-it-happen&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put simply, a ban is when Nintendo decides not to let a specific console or Nintendo account use its online services. Most bans associated with hacking are console bans, meaning that the specific console that Nintendo has banned will be unable to use Nintendos online services, including the eshop, game updates, and online play. Nintendo reserves the right to withhold these services per their &lt;a href=&#34;https://accounts.nintendo.com/term/eula/US?lang=en-US&#34;&gt;user agreement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-what-does-nintendo-ban-consoles-for&#34; &gt;2. What does Nintendo ban consoles for?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#2-what-does-nintendo-ban-consoles-for&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following actions will cause an immediate ban of your Nintendo Switch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Piracy of any sort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homebrew NSPs (installed to the home menu)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing user icon through Homebrew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sketchy eShop behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following actions will not result in an immediate ban, but will still result in a ban:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modding online games&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cheating in online games&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearing error logs after theyve been uploaded to Nintendo (this may extend to using both emuMMC and sysMMC online, due to mismatched logs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following actions have not resulted in a ban (so far):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atmosphere itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homebrew (via title takeover)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom themes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom sysmodules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mods/cheating in offline games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overclocking with sys-clk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;EmuMMC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to Val on the ReSwitched Discord server for this list)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-how-does-nintendo-know-i-did-any-of-the-things-they-ban-for&#34; &gt;3. How does Nintendo know I did any of the things they ban for?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#3-how-does-nintendo-know-i-did-any-of-the-things-they-ban-for&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nintendo filled the Switch with telemetry systems. Telemetry systems basically monitor what the user does on the console, including what games they install, what games they play, and a bunch of other data too. The Nintendo Switch stores this data constantly, even while offline, and will send these data logs to Nintendo as soon as it connects to the internet and Nintendos servers. This means that if a bannable action is performed on the Switch (even while offline) and the console connects to the internet at any point afterward, even briefly, Nintendo will receive the telemetry log and ban the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-how-do-i-prevent-getting-banned&#34; &gt;4. How do I prevent getting banned?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#4-how-do-i-prevent-getting-banned&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are essentially two ways to prevent getting banned. The first is to avoid performing any of the actions that Nintendo bans for on your Switch. The second is to keep your console permanently offline so that even if you take a bannable action, Nintendo will never be sent the telemetry log and will never find out about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5what-is-an-emunandemummc-can-it-prevent-me-from-getting-banned&#34; &gt;5.What is an emuNAND/emuMMC? Can it prevent me from getting banned?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#5what-is-an-emunandemummc-can-it-prevent-me-from-getting-banned&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;NAND is simply a type of data storage that is used in a variety of electronic devices. eMMC is the type of NAND that is used in the Switch as its internal data storage. All of the Switchs data is stored on its eMMC, which is an internal component of the Switch. This internal storage is sometimes referred to as the system NAND/eMMC or sysNAND/sysMMC. An emuNAND or emuMMC (emulated NAND or emulated eMMC) is a copy of the SysNAND stored on the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the telemetry logs are stored in the Switchs NAND, an emuNAND is useful because it allows you to have two copies of the Switchs internal storage. Your sysNAND can be used for online play and eshop purchases while your emuNAND can be used for CFW and hacking and be kept permanently offline. This lets you have the best of both worlds! If you followed the recommended CFW setup on &lt;a href=&#34;https://nh-server.github.io/switch-guide/&#34;&gt;Nintendo Homebrews guide&lt;/a&gt;, you should already have an emuNAND set up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-so-i-cant-get-banned-if-i-use-an-emunand-right&#34; &gt;6. So I cant get banned if I use an emuNAND, right?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#6-so-i-cant-get-banned-if-i-use-an-emunand-right&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An emuNAND is a tool to help prevent bans, it is not a silver bullet. You have to keep your emuNAND permanently offline or it wont help you very much. It is also important to note that even though the internal storage of your sysNAND and emuNAND are separate, they are still copies of the same system with the same unique identifiers. If Nintendo bans your emuNAND then your sysNAND gets banned too and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-but-what-if-i-want-to-use-online-homebrew-tools-like-ftp-or-the-homebrew-store&#34; &gt;7. But what if I want to use online homebrew tools like FTP or the Homebrew Store?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#7-but-what-if-i-want-to-use-online-homebrew-tools-like-ftp-or-the-homebrew-store&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you still want to use your internet connection on your always-offline console (or emuNAND), there is a way to do so. You just need to make sure that even though your console may be connected to the internet, it wont be able to connect to Nintendos servers and therefore wont be able to send the telemetry logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommended way to do this is 90DNS, which are custom DNS servers that allow connection to the internet, but block Nintendos servers. You can find instructions on setting up 90DNS &lt;a href=&#34;https://nh-server.github.io/switch-guide/extras/blocking_updates/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-what-about-incognito&#34; &gt;8. What about Incognito?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#8-what-about-incognito&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Incognito is not recommended for a variety of reasons. It functions by blanking your consoles PRODINFO, which is console-unique data that your console requires to boot. If Incognito goes wrong, it can result in damage to your console, even an unrecoverable brick. Additionally, Incognito is less reliable than 90DNS as it depends on Nintendo rejecting telemetry logs from consoles with blanked PRODINFO and while that is currently true, Nintendo may change this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of Atmosphere 0.12.0, a virtual PRODINFO blanking feature was included, which is safer than Incognito, but still not a viable replacement for 90DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Thanks to noirscape on the Nintendo Homebrew Discord server for the explanation of why Incognito is bad)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-my-console-is-banned-how-can-i-unban-it&#34; &gt;9. My console is banned. How can I unban it?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#9-my-console-is-banned-how-can-i-unban-it&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You cant. Sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-i-performed-a-bannable-action-on-my-offline-sysnand-but-now-i-want-to-go-online-what-do-i-do&#34; &gt;10. I performed a bannable action on my offline sysNAND but now I want to go online. What do I do?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#10-i-performed-a-bannable-action-on-my-offline-sysnand-but-now-i-want-to-go-online-what-do-i-do&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Restore a clean NAND backup of the system from before you performed the bannable action. You can find instructions for doing that &lt;a href=&#34;https://nh-server.github.io/switch-guide/extras/nandrestore/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the Switchs stock factory format feature does not erase telemetry logs and will not protect you from a ban.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-what-if-i-lost-my-nand-backup-or-never-made-one&#34; &gt;11. What if I lost my NAND backup or never made one?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#11-what-if-i-lost-my-nand-backup-or-never-made-one&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You messed up. Make sure to make a NAND backup for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is &lt;a href=&#34;https://suchmememanyskill.github.io/guides/unbrick/#system-wipe&#34;&gt;a method for manually resetting the NANDs data&lt;/a&gt;, but it is not as reliable as restoring a NAND backup and should not be your preferred option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-so-if-i-follow-the-advice-here-im-guaranteed-not-to-get-banned&#34; &gt;12. So if I follow the advice here Im guaranteed not to get banned?
&lt;span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#12-so-if-i-follow-the-advice-here-im-guaranteed-not-to-get-banned&#34;&gt;
        &lt;svg viewBox=&#34;0 0 28 23&#34; height=&#34;100%&#34; width=&#34;19&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M10 13a5 5 0 0 0 7.54.54l3-3a5 5 0 0 0-7.07-7.07l-1.72 1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M14 11a5 5 0 0 0-7.54-.54l-3 3a5 5 0 0 0 7.07 7.07l1.71-1.71&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-miterlimit=&#34;10&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing in life is guaranteed. The information here is based on quite a lot of experience, but Nintendo can always decide to change what actions they consider bannable or add new ways of gathering telemetry. Part of hacking your console means accepting a little risk and taking responsibility for your decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
